Test 4. This is the IELTS listening test. You will hear a number of different
recordings and you will have to answer questions on what you hear. There will be
time for you to read the instructions and questions and you will have a chance
to check your work. All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts. At the end of the test you will be given 10 minutes to
transfer your answers to the answer sheet. Now turn to part 1.
Part 1. You will hear a man phoning the owner of a holiday cottage. First you
have some time to look at questions 1 to 6.
Hello. Oh hello. I was hoping to speak to Jack Fitzgerald about renting a cottage.
I'm his wife Shirley and we own the cottages together so I'm sure I can help
you. Great. My name's Tom. Some friends of ours rented Granary Cottage from you
last year and they thought it was great so my wife and I are hoping to come in
May for a week. What date did you have in mind? The week beginning the 14th if
possible. I'll just check. I'm sorry Tom it's already booked that week. It's free
the week beginning the 28th though for seven nights. In fact that's the only
time you could have it in May. Oh well we could manage that I think. We just need
to change a couple of things. How much would it cost? That's the beginning of
high season so it'd be £550 for the week. Ah that's a bit more than we
wanted to pay I'm afraid. We've budgeted up to £500 for accommodation. Well we've
just finished converting another building into a cottage which we're
calling Cherville Cottage. Sorry what was that again? Cherville. C-H-E-R-V for
Victor I-L. Oh that's a herb isn't it? That's right. It grows fairly wild around
here. You could have that for the week you want for £480. Okay so could you
tell me something about it please? Of course. The building was built as a
garage. It's a little smaller than Granary Cottage. So that must sleep two
people as well. That's right. There's a double bedroom. Does it have a garden? Yes
you get to it from the living room through French doors and we provide two
deck chairs. We hope to build a patio in the near future but I wouldn't like to
guarantee it'll be finished by May. Okay. The front door opens onto the old
farmyard and parking isn't a problem. There's plenty of room at the front for
that. There are some trees and potted plants there.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation you have some time to look
at questions seven to ten.
you
Now listen and answer questions seven to ten.
What about facilities in the cottage? It has standard things like a cooker and
fridge I presume. In the kitchen area there's a fridge freezer and we've just
put in an electric cooker. Is there a washing machine? Yes there's also a TV in
the living room which plays DVDs too. The bathroom is too small for a bath so
there's a shower instead. I think a lot of people prefer that nowadays anyway.
It's more environmentally friendly isn't it? Unless you spend half the day
in it. Exactly. What about heating? It sometimes gets quite cool at that time
of year. There's central heating and if you want to light a fire there's a stove.
We can provide all the wood you need for it. It smells so much nicer than coal and
it makes the room very cozy. We've got one in our own house. That sounds very
pleasant. Perhaps we should come in the winter to make the most of it. Yes we
find we don't want to go out when we've got the fire burning. There are some
attractive views from the cottage which I haven't mentioned. There's a famous
stone bridge. It's one of the oldest in the region and you can see it from the
living room. It isn't far away. The bedroom window looks in the opposite
direction and has a lovely view of the hills and the monument at the top. Well
that all sounds perfect. I'd like to book it please. Would you want to deposit? Yes
we ask for 30% to secure your booking so that'll be £144.
And when would you like the rest of the money? You're coming in May so the
last day of March please. Fine. Excellent. Could I just take your details so that I can...
That is the end of part one. You now have half a minute to check your answers to
part one.
you